And I decided to just be a little bit diligent with the
information and applied it before starting the program.
So yesterday I closed on a deal. It's a $1,500 deal.
It's small, but yeah, I use what you, what you,
what you're teaching us in detail. And yeah, I got a win already.
So just wanted to share that with you
Guys. Awesome, man. Congrats. Good to hear.
Glad, uh, glad some of this information's paying off and uh,
I'd really do love to hear it. Um, awesome.
So appreciate you sharing that nester. Um, so, okay,
so for today's agenda, I figure today we'll kind of slow it down a little bit.
I apologize if there's noise in the background too.
There's some work happening in my house, but we'll just power through it. Um,
slow down a little bit today. Like I said,
we're gonna add some sessions on the end of this. So, um, two main things.
I got like a few more slides to get through just to kind of tie a bow on all of
the official trainings for this, this one, open it up. Um,
there's been some questions in Slack from some folks.
I just wanna make sure that I'm really taking the time to go through answer
them. Um,
also too is an opportunity for things that you still want to see from
this program, right? Um, 'cause we still have time.
I'm happy to put together some additional information. Uh,
whatever it is you all want the rest of the time here is completely yours.
Again, we've got a couple of these, I think four of these sessions set. Um,
I'm happy to, happy to tailor them.
However you all want my time is yours to spend. Uh,
some of you have messaged me and apologize, please don't apologize. Um,
you all paid good money to be here,
so my time is yours to use however you see fit.
So that being said, let's just jump on over the slides, get through,
get through the last couple ones here, and, uh,
tie a bow on these slide decks. 'cause I hate slide decks.
I hate going through 'em, but they do make sure that I stay on task here.
So I think we're on day is this day, five day, day four, day five, losing count.
Um, so the last part of this process, again, we've been through the, uh,
analysis process. We've been through the proposal process. Um,
now we're getting to the point where we have the proposal call.
We'll talk a little bit about that 'cause I don't think we really spoke too much
about it on the proposal part for the most part. Again,
it's not too, too difficult to run the proposal calls for the most part.
Once you've got the proposal done,
all we're doing is really reviewing it with them. I like to keep them quick.
I don't like to go through slide by slide. I think it's, it's,
it's pretty boring. Uh,
what I like to do is really just hit the main parts and that's gonna be the
scope of work. Just reiterating their goals, right?
Getting buy-in for a last time on their goals.
And then the pricing and how we arrived on the pricing. Again,
we wanna try and hit the points where we're forecasting that they're gonna have
the most questions, um, and also the most objections as well.
So we wanna try and get ahead of that.
Just review it with them and look them in the face and ask 'em if they have any
questions. It's just gonna save you a lot of back and forth in the future. Uh,
when it comes to these types of things, uh,
we'll talk a little about some follow-ups and then just kind of closing out the
deal. So for the, yeah, so in terms of the follow-ups, again,
after you have the proposal call again, you can also do a loom. I uploaded a,
a loom example into PO that you can check out. Um,
it was one of the proposals that we actually looked at last time for the paid
search deal.
We spent a good amount of time actually going through the paid search stuff
that,
that's pretty fun 'cause I haven't done that on any sort of trainings lately.
Hopefully that was helpful. Um, you know, again,
as the blueprint continues to evolve,
SS e o is obviously gonna be always be our core,
but we wanna make sure that we're helping you all stay in the best position to
succeed. Not just for your businesses, but also for your clients.
And sometimes that means doing a little bit of extra work or services to make
sure that they are getting the best possible results possible because you're
getting the results, then you're gonna keep getting paid.
So when it comes to follow-ups,
I wanna touch on this real quick because we,
I've got a lot of questions about this over the years. Um, again,
this goes back to kinda like the Wolf of Wall Street stuff and I see people all
the time on like Twitter threads and LinkedIn threads,
like comment for our like follow-up strategy.
If people aren't interested, you can follow up until you're blue in the face.
It's not gonna make a difference, right? So there's really no,
there's no silver magic bullet here.
And sometimes you have to put yourself in the shoes of the prospect when
you're following up. So first and foremost,
this is why it's so important on the proposal caller before that to ask when you
can have the expected decision date from them.
And the reason is because if you can get that date,
which you're not always gonna get, in all fairness, you know,
a lot of the times people are gonna beat around the bush. They're gonna say, oh,
I don't know, I have to check this and that, try and get something right?
Even if they set say something like, well, I still have to talk to my boss. Um,
or there's still a number of other people that I have to run up the ladder with.
I have to check budgets to say, okay, well how about a week from Wednesday?
Does that give you enough time to do that? Because again,
we wanna get that date because once we have that date,
now we have much more skin in the game to send follow-ups.
'cause sometimes with follow-ups you can get carried away.
It's happened to me before. I've, I've sent people to go f sometimes. Um,
because you put so much time and energy and emotion into these proposals,
sometimes, and sometimes, you know, we talked about this in the beginning,
sometimes we can get a little bit overly emotional.
We can get married to the deal, right? Something that we don't wanna do.
It's very difficult though because again,
you put so much of your time and energy into this, uh,
that a lot of the times you can just kind of see right,
a little bit when people ghost sue or people are not giving the responses that
you want. So if you have that date,
then it gives us a concrete reason to follow up because again,
now we can hold them more accountable.
So a large part of this too is trying to get the us to hold them accountable to
what they ask us for.
My biggest frustration point I've vented to my partner about this number of
times is law firms, man, they, they come to us. We never do outbound.
So people always come to us. Lemme just pull the chat over here. Um,
uh, people come to us, they request the work, they request the analysis,
they show up to all the calls.
I'm putting so much energy and emotion and I'm putting more and more skin in the
game every time we get down this process.
So for them to ghost at the end is a very frustrating thing.
But when you have that date,
it allows you to hold them accountable for it and allows you to follow up
against that to make sure that we can actually get a response from them just as
professional adults. So, uh, I always say too,
after you send a proposal,
you have the right to follow up incessantly because you put so much
time and energy into it. Um, don't feel bad about it.
But of course we always wanna be kind, uh, respectful, courteous,
because at the same time, you know, if somebody's ghosting on you,
we don't always know what happened in their life. Maybe they lost someone,
maybe they're going through a divorce,
maybe they just had a baby that you didn't know about. Um,
there's a whole lot of things that people are dealing with in their personal
lives that is way more important than what we're doing here. So it's always,
always important that, and again, I've made this mistake myself, so I'm,
I'm speaking from experience here.
We always wanna make sure that we're being kind and respectful with the,
with the follow-ups.
We never wanna make any sort of assumptions that they're ghosting us or that
they're not interested. Just be kind. That,
that's all I'm saying because sometimes a lot of the times actually with some of
these deals, it can take months and months and months.
I actually just got one not that long ago.
That was two years after I sent a proposal that they came back and finally said
yes to the proposal. Of course I had to re-scope it, but the point is,
is that people always come back in the future. So, um,
here's one that I I've used before in the past that's,
that's worked pretty well. And this is after I've sent a couple of follow-ups,
literally with a follow-up. Uh, it's just something along the lines of, Hey,
just wanna follow up. You know, we agreed on this date,
you told me that you have a decision by Wednesday. Do you need any help?
Do you have any questions? I'm happy to jump on a call. What else can I do?
Right? Just be helpful. Uh, we don't need to push them for an actual decision,
just kind of leave it a little bit open-ended, trying to continue to be helpful.
Um, and then I'll, I'll literally send an email every day. I don't care.
Send an email every day.
Sometimes we'll send a text messages if they're not responding.
This one just says, we've sent a few emails.
This is after you get to like four or five, you know,
over a couple of weeks and they've just sent nothing.
Sent a few emails following up the proposal question.
We haven't gotten a response. I'm sure you're busy. Could you hit me back again?
We haven't gotten a response. I'm sure you're busy.
You can see how we're still being nice and respectful and polite here.
We're not being like, yo, like I sent you this information and like,
you totally ghosted me. Like, what the f bro? Um, I'm sure you're busy.
Could you hit me back with a number 1, 2, 3 that best describes your response?
One, leave me alone. Two, two busy. Three, I'll write you back in a week.
Short and sweet talk soon. Right? Uh, so again,
it just kind of like even further pushes it on them to be like, yo, just,
just gimme a number here, like one, two, or three.
Just let me know what you're feeling. Um,
and the one that always works for me too at the end is I just usually tell them
like, once I've sent,
actually just went through this with a law firm and that ju has just ended up
closing them where, uh, it, it's been about four months.
And this was a monster proposal that I put together all by the request.
Mind you, like, they requested design, they wanted all this stuff.
They requested so much work. And I had told them along the,
everything that I've told you during this process, I, I, I went through, I,
I held 'em accountable. Um, you know,
I told them that's gonna take a lot of my time.
I told them that I'm gonna put a lot,
the whole nine and they still just completely ghost me at the end.
And I basically just said at the end, I said, Hey look, you know, um,
I know you're busy. I know you're, you've got a lot of clients going on,
but I also put a lot of time into this too.
So at this point I have no choice but to re remove you from my follow-up list
because the proposal's expired.
It's been four months and everything I put in there is no longer gonna be valid.
So if you're still interested, just reply with a yes.
That's all you have to do. If not, I'll take your silence as, uh,
a not interested. They replied with a yes, of course. Um,
and now we're in the process of closing that contract. So, um, you know,
mind you,
I could have lost my mind and I was this close to losing my mind on them too.
'cause it was probably one of the more frustrating ones that I've been through
with the amount of work and scoping I had to do. Uh, but again, it's,
it's important to just cooler heads always prevail, um,
especially in these situations. Got a couple questions.
Can I add some color to that?
Yeah, Andrew, please fire away.
And this is law firms, but it may apply to other, other verticals too.
Um, and I've, I've typically dealt with mid to large sized law firms,
so that's gonna be at least 50 lawyers, more likely a hundred plus lawyers.
And the whole process just gets more glacial, right?
Just trying to push things through because they've gotta go through multiple
tiers. And,
and my contact person typically has been someone in marketing,
usually the director or the, or a managing, you know,
someone who's doing the marketing manager kind of level stuff.
And all the firms that I've dealt with are absolutely swamped with work.
So they've got a basket full of things that are super important and
they're generally trying to put out fires and how do you surface something that
actually can impact their top and bottom line and get noise. And,
and most of these folks are just so burnt out that they just don't really care
or have time to care or whatever. And it's so, it's a tough, it's a tough space.
It's, it's, this is probably, I know there's a question there,
but I'll disagree with you for a second that this is probably the worst of the
worst in all the industries that I've worked with in terms of proposal ghosting.
It, it's, it's, it's incredibly frustrated. Something that a,
a few things that I've seen and I've tested and I've used, and also, again,
being on the client side, that has really got my attention. One,
we talked about this before, during the process, right?
When somebody's not qualified, not interested,
you move them in your active campaign or your email provider for future updates.
Something that I love that this design shop did, um,
'cause I've been helping vet agencies for this company I'm working with is every
quarter they send out a, a,
a playbook for design in terms of what's working right now.
Design trends that they've seen, um,
and also work that they've done for clients before, like,
like over the last quarter. And like sharing client wins.
They do it in a way that's also not like beating my chest.
And it's beautifully done. They're an amazing design shop.
So they basically build like a magazine of, of their work.
I find that to be incredibly effective because what it does,
it kind of reengages that beginning level interest that usually catches your
attention in the beginning, right? I, I, I really, really like that.
And I think that's also very passive way to not aggressively follow up with
people, but but to kind of like reengage that spark.
Because essentially what's happening here too, Andrew, is like you said,
it's just not a priority for them, right? Like,
they're probably still interested,
but at this moment we all know that like decision making is actually something
that's very exhausting as a leader. Um,
and you get fatigued from it to the point where like, you know, they,
they talk about how Steve Jobs always wore the same thing over and over again
because he had so many decisions on his plate on a daily basis that he wanted to
remove that decision fatigue and just wear the same thing every day.
And that was one less thing for him to worry about. Go ahead Andrew.
It looks like you have a follow up.
Yeah, and I was just gonna say, like one of these clients, um,
I've had for, I've had several clients for 10 plus years, right?
And literally one of them, I've watched them go through four CMOs,
like four directors of marketing.
Like they just chew through them because they're just burning these guys out and
that's just what their day job, you know, that like, just,
just putting the.dot in the i's and crossing the t's on,
on what they've gotta do every day, let alone take on something new. So it's a,
it, it's a challenge and I've always thought that maybe I'm talking to the wrong
people. I gotta talk to the, to the partners, the managing partners and,
and show them what their competitors are doing and really appeal to their ego.
And you know, my spidey sense is maybe that's gonna, that would work better,
but it's just trying to get to them. This is the challenge.
Yeah. And keep in mind also Andrew Rudd is that if you're selling a service,
if they're so busy as it is, right?
And you're selling a service that's gonna put more working clients on their
plate,
it's probably not gonna be something that they're gonna be overly ecstatic about
signing, right?
So yeah, I agree. I'm, I'm, I'm thinking quality, like, you know,
you can be busy, you know, doing nothing.
Well, I think, I think, let me put this in another context for you too, right?
So think about remarketing, right? Let's say you're looking at sneakers,
for example,
the common thought practice is with remarketing is to remarket the exact same
product that you were looking at. Now, granted, if you like adding it to cart,
you,
you were on the page for a certain amount of time that that drives a certain
level of intent, right? Maybe you're on your phone, you didn't want,
you don't have your credit card on you, whatever, it's,
but for the most part you convert it like 1% on those pages.
So the assumption is that if we just get the product back in front of 'em,
they'll buy it. And I actually think that's the wrong assumption, right?
Maybe not for e-commerce, but like more for like what we're doing.
My thought has always been what we put in front of them,
they have the chance to buy it. What we put in front of them didn't work.
We should come back to them with a different value proposition or a different
offer, right? Or a different angle.
And I think that's probably hyper relevant here, right?
Instead of just like hammering being like, Hey, I'm gonna get you more clients.
I'm gonna get you more clients, I'm gonna get you more clients. It's okay,
they're super busy. Maybe they don't like, they, they care about clients.
That's what, those are the conversations that we had. But like,
maybe we need to reiterate and reframe this a little bit more to say,
I'm here to take stuff off your plate.
I know that you think that signing this contract is ideally gonna put more work
on your plate, but it's the opposite. Like, I am here to be a stress reliever.
I'm here to take work off your plate so you can focus on doing this work, right?
So there's different ways to frame that, there's different ways to,
to communicate that. But I,
I think that's an important discussion and an important thing for you to think
through is, how can I reframe this so it doesn't seem like, 'cause it sucks.
I agree.
Like you sign a contract with an agency and it's like a blitz creep for the
first two weeks of like onboarding conversations and like digging up documents.
Like it sucks. Um, you know, so like trying to,
trying to find the right wording to frame that in a way for them that doesn't
feel like you're coming on to be more burden on their plate, right?
Um, just a thought in, in, in terms of how, in terms of how that could go. Um,
so, uh, Connor asks, have you had success with that level of follow up? Yeah,
I mean it's mixed, right? I mean, for the most part, you know,
everyone's got their own different timelines. Kinda like Andrew said too, right?
There's, there's so much happening because this is so important to us.
We assume it's so important to everyone else too.
And especially if they reach out to you, they request proposal,
they're showing up for the calls, they're super engaged, stuff happens,
you know, so like to me, a follow-up isn't, like, isn't,
like I said,
it's not this like hard close thing where like we need to push scarcity.
It's just trying to stay top of mind. I i,
if you go through my inbox in my email,
like there's emails that I have from two months ago that I know are important
and I know that I need to do something about,
but I just physically can't,
like my brain just physically will not allow me to take on that big of a
commitment at that moment. Um, so other things too are like,
again, connecting on social media with them, right? Is a small thing.
You if it, especially if it's a big pitch, right? Connect on social media. Um,
you know, if they're posting,
give 'em a little like just kind of like let them know that you're still there,
right?
You just wanna try and stay top of mind because if you push too hard on some
people then you're probably gonna push 'em away in this instance, right? Again,
that level of followup that I do with sometimes saying,
look at this proposal's gonna expire. Um, we do need a decision.
We don't have to lock anything in now. You don't have to pay anything now.
You don't have to sign anything now I just want to know if this is still
interest to you so I can earmark this. Because if not,
we're gonna have to move forward and we're gonna have to start this whole
process over again, right? Whether it's me or with somebody else.
And you probably don't wanna do that 'cause it's gonna be a lot more work.
So if this is something that you want,
if this is something that you're interested in, just let me know. Um,
and I'll follow up again in a month and we'll pick this conversation up.
It doesn't have to be right now, but like for our process,
for this proposal that we sent,
there is a timeline on this because if you come back in six months from now,
then you know, our prices are gonna go up. So let's just lock something in,
let's get some sort of commitment from you so that way we can,
we can move forward when the time is right for you.
Gonna go through the questions.
Connor said Predis question,
when you don't advertise your prices on your website,
how do you handle responding to prospects who are asking for price ranges prior
to talking to them? I, I mean I gave it to him.
I actually just had a call with a guy that was a one call close man that was a,
it was a rare thing yesterday. I had a one call I wish I recorded.
It was a one call close. The guy came in cold,
actually he came in through a blog post on the website.
I don't even know which one,
but he came through a blog post on the website and he, uh,
during the disco call, he was,
he was very adamant about about pricing and I just kind of threw him a range.
He needed some technical work, he needed some, some,
some kind of content review. And I told him it was probably about 10,000 bucks.
Um, so that is how I handle,
I just told him straight up and I always like to go a little over two. Um,
because yeah,
I mean ideally we're gonna be charging a 50 50,000 over the course of the year,
right? So I just, I, and I understand that too because sometimes as a,
as a consumer, as a person, I'm like, look, everything looks good. This is cool,
but how much does it cost, right? I don't wanna drag my,
I don't like just 'cause I don't have my price on my website,
even though I do on the, on the law firm website. Um,
I don't want to be one of those people that's like, oh well,
like I have to go through the scoping and this and that. Like just tell them,
uh, because it's gonna save you a lot of time going forward in the future.
Go ahead Connor.
What about when it's so unclear of like what the scope actually is?
Like a lot of times it could be really simple or it could be so
much more like, I'm afraid
Go ahead.
I'm afraid of throwing them a high too high of a number that's just going to
qualify them out.
Yeah, so I just pitched 'em a foundational sprint, a foot in the door,
a foot in the door offer in that, in that sense because that way I get in,
close the work, get money coming through,
and then we can scope the full thing out.
Okay.
So like, if somebody's just like, and, and again like I said,
I get that as a consumer too because pricing is o often the
most kind of important thing here. And if the,
I see something that I like and I'm interested in,
I don't want to go through like a three week process of like scoping a proposal.
'cause then I feel bad too 'cause I'm like,
you could've just saved your time upfront by just telling me the price.
I would've told you yes or no right away. You know? Um, so again,
you should have a pretty good idea. 15 minutes. This just,
this will just come in experience more and more, but like,
you should be showing up to the disco call,
like with some sort of pricing in your head that is
gonna scope out against it. And Noah said the same thing. He said,
I've been pitching a strategy sprint,
which allows me to get them a firm price for our cus for a custom tailed
solution for their business and goals. It's been working, yeah,
it works really well.
And that's why I said that that's why closing guy on the first call,
because then I just hyperfocused on that conversation about what he's gonna get
from that. And he was like, send me the information.
I'm going on vacation this week, but, um, you know,
I'll sign the contract today and we'll get started when I get back. Uh,
Andrew said, well, my business did custom software gigs,
I always build for requirements as a deliverable. Um, Andrew also asked,
has anyone ever tried to build for the analysis phase?
Sometimes I think we're giving away for free for the rest of the work. Uh,
Noah said, just got paid for two of them at $2,500 each. Yeah.
So I kind of alluded to this, and this is something that, you know,
I'm testing more and more, um, Andrew, especially for these large,
like that law firm man that, uh, I've been chasing down.
Like I wish I charged them for it for the analysis because,
you know, like to, to do a found,
like if I'm pitching a foundational sprint to this guy,
like I'm not gonna charge him to do the analysis, right?
But for that one where I had to do like a, a UX analysis, I, that was like,
I'm still kicking myself to this day for not charging 'em 500 or a thousand
bucks for it. Um, and it's guaranteed money back, you know, um,
for them either apply to the retainer and you can even throw in kickers in terms
of like, look, if we, if we move forward,
then I'll like apply this as two x towards your retainer. Um, uh,
but if not, I'm gonna keep it. Uh, or like, if not, like, you know,
when you gimme a decision, like you'll get the money back, you know? Um,
it's something that I know a lot of, a lot of agencies do, it's just,
it's very touch and go, like I said, because it's almost ironic,
but like the bigger the proposal, the more necessary that is.
But at the same time, it's like the bigger the proposal,
they're probably also working with or talking to other agencies that are maybe
not doing it. It's just, it's, it's, it's, it's a roll the dice, you know,
again, like I'm working with this company Jeter to build a rewards and loyalty
app, right? And man,
we've gone through probably like 10 different firms that we've interviewed.
And I know for a fact if the one of the firms was like,
we need a thousand dollars, they'd been like, no. So, you know,
it's, it's, it's, it's very, very, very, very, very hit or miss, you know, um,
just depending.
So in regards to the, after this, um,
we send over an agreement, the template's up there, it's very straightforward.
I don't,
Connor do you still have a question or is that just your hand raised from
before? Okay. Um,
so it's important to get something writing. Again,
it's literally just taking the scope from the proposal and the pricing.
I just literally copy and paste it into a, a Word document. Um,
it's important to have something documented just in case of future disputes,
something that they can sign their name on. Um, a quick note on that too though,
is that most of these deals for the most part are not gonna be anything that's
gonna really protect either party from any sort of legal dispute. We're talking,
if it's less than 50,000 bucks over the course of a year for the grand scheme of
things, it's probably, it's just not worth getting attorneys,
attorneys involved over. Um,
so I don't really look at agreement necessarily as legal protection,
but more of, um, you know, valuation. For example, if,
if somebody wanted to get money from a bank, uh,
if you wanted to sell the agency,
it's always good to have documentation in writing for the, for the, the, the,
the run rate and lifecycle of these contracts.
I know a lot of purchasers will look at that. Um,
month to month agreements can be a tougher sell if you're trying to sell your
business because they want some sort of, again, runway after the Passover, uh,
of the, of the deal. But even that, I, my, when my agency was bought,
I had 12 month contracts in place and as soon as I was bought within two months,
half of those turned out.
And it's not like we were gonna chase them down because engaging your an
attorney on that costs a minimum of five to grand just to, just to get started.
Law firms are very expensive. So again, it's more for peace of mind.
It's also just to really finalize the expectations,
the scope of work and the pricing. Um, so again, we have a template for that.
I'm sure a lot of you do as well populate it, it takes two seconds,
send it to 'em for e-sign. Um,
and sometimes you don't even have to get e-sign of it. At my old agency,
we used to just send it to 'em via email and say, um, you know,
this email is binding. If, if you reply with the words like, yes, I agree,
then you know, this, this, uh,
locks the contract and that's enough of a paper trail also for, you know,
legal purposes, what have you. And it also saves a little bit of time,
um, stay away from month to month. Um, you don't need a contract for that deal,
but it's also not a great business model.
Eating my own words on this one a little bit,
because we are pretty much month to month,
but we still do have agreements in place. Again,
what I meant by that is you just ha should have something in writing,
even if you're month to month, right?
It's just good to have something in writing. Um,
I know month to month is like a big selling point for a lot of prospects and
clients, but for the most part man,
like those are probably not gonna be the great ones. Like if,
if somebody's like, yeah, I'm signing you either because you're,
you're month to month versus other people,
the problem with that is that when you, like,
so much of our work is front loaded here, not just in terms of deliverables,
but also like the mental bandwidth of taking on a new client and the energy of
taking on a new client. Um,
especially once you have a team in terms of communicating it,
going through the onboarding process. You know, my team and I,
we have a standing Monday meeting and a Friday meeting and on every Monday
meeting, whenever it, or Friday, if we're onboarding a new client,
I spend a good like 20 to 30 minutes just dissecting the
proposal, um, talking about the business model, really,
really making sure that my team understands the client's service, product offer,
whatever it is. Because if they don't,
then it's really gonna be hard for them to build any sort of content around
that. Um, so then you just send the in, uh, send it and then invoice.
We use QuickBooks, we send everything through QuickBooks. Um,
lot of great products out there. We got off of Stripe because of the fees. Um,
so we use, well it's says Stripe here, but that's not, that's not correct. Um,
we use QuickBooks for that. So we have an accountant to, um,
outsourced accountant if anybody needs an accountant firm. By the way,
our accountant is amazing. Um, very affordable as well.
I think it's like a thousand bucks a month or something. Um,
I think there are fees with QuickBooks, Noah, but it's not like Stripe fees.
Stripe is like three, three something percent.
We're actually working on getting off of that blueprint too. 'cause it, it,
it takes a, it takes a big chunk, especially when you're doing a couple hundred,
hundred, a hundred grand a month. Like it, it takes a, a really big chunk. Um,
so we use QuickBooks. QuickBooks is fine with that. So our process is sales,
um, gets a proposal accepted,
we then put together your agreement and send it to 'em.
And as soon as that agreement is assigned and then gets passed over via Slack to
our accountant who's in Slack for us, again, completely outsourced for,
but she's, she's great. She's in there. She sends the invoice.
Once the invoice is, uh, paid and signed, then it goes, goes over to our,
our delivery team for the onboarding email, which is also inside the blueprint.
This is just an internal announcement, uh, if you have a team, right? Um,
I think it's really important for a couple reasons to one,
celebrate wins, right?
I think closed deals is like a good morale booster, um,
for the team, for the sales rep, for whoever's closing. I think it's just, it's,
it's just good energy in the business when you're sharing wins and closing
deals. Um, and you also want to pass that energy, I think to your delivery team.
So they're a little bit excited, especially too, as a,
and when you go through the sales process and you have a lot of these
conversations, um,
you get a little bit of a kind of an emotional buy-in to these clients and you
really wanna see them do well.
So I think it's good for you to pass that to the team.
So we just do an announcement internally. This is our, well, our sales rep now,
um, just announcing one in Slack, you know,
just telling you a little bit about the business, a little bit of what we did.
And then again, the team call that we have twice a week. Then we'll go through,
um, very, very detailed the proposal, the scope of work, um,
this is before the project plan is built too.
And then I'll just like also brain dump all the notes that I had so the team can
understand as much context as possible about these clients.
So that's it for the presentation deck. Um,
go ahead Andrew. Let me just, uh, stop sharing my screen.
Let's go through some questions.
Uh, I posted this in chat too, just,
just wondering if people have played around with different, um, billing, uh,
style. So let's take a sprint or a six month or whatever.
Let's say it's nine K and we,
we all know it's front loaded 'cause we do the most work in that first month and
then it tapers down and, but we've flattened over the payment.
I'm wondering how playing around with having like the, it's,
it's kind of obvious to the client too that you're going on week, you know,
month four to six, you're really just doing repeat and rinse, right? And, um,
so I'm thinking about putting a bigger, you know,
amount in the first couple months and then have it taper down for, you know,
four, five,
and six through the amount that we're actually working at that point in time for
a little more transparency and maybe that,
I don't know how it's gonna be received,
but has anybody else played with that kind of idea? I
Don't,
I don't know if I fully understand what you meant by taper down if anyone else
did, please.
Well, like the first month,
maybe 2.5 K and then two K and then 1.5 and then the last month,
you're just doing a thousand each month to reflect the actual amount of work
that you're doing as opposed to having it 1.5 K over six months. Like just even.
Oh, okay. Yeah, I mean, so,
so yes, we've done that. So, okay, so I'll, I'll,
I'll kind of wa I see what you're saying now. So for us,
if it's 9,000 bucks but over six months, then yeah, you can,
you can definitely do it like that because the upfront number isn't
overwhelming, right? But if it's a bigger deal, right? So, you know,
I would say our average deal is probably like, call it 50, right?
So it's 50 over six and the first month is in 25,000.
25,000. Then they're like, it, it just becomes overwhelming to pay that.
But if it's a deal that size, absolutely,
and I think that's a great incentive too, right? Because then it,
they understand that you're doing it, you know exactly as you're working,
you know, et cetera. It just, it's just,
to me it's all about what that client's threshold is for cash spent
in a, in a given time. That's, I think that's really what it comes down to,
you know,
So it's just payment options. You can say this is the way the work goes,
we can split it out evenly over six months or three months, whatever it is.
Or you can pay up front, whatever. Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
And I, I actually ties into I think a lot of what,
like Noah's questions were about sprints versus retainers, right?
Is that when I go through the pricing sheet, right,
it shows the exact amount per month that we're doing from a,
a worker billables, right? So I'll,
and this is what I go over on the proposal call and I'll tell them, you know,
I just wanna show you this so you understand exactly what we're doing and when
and what you're getting and when.
And I also want you to understand how the breakdown of work is so you understand
the flow work, you understand, you know,
how the deliverables will be coming and what we'll be focused on each month also
to understand all our level of effort.
And I'll tell them that the first couple of months, you know,
if it's a six or nine month proposal,
that it's always gonna be front loaded in the first two months.
And I want them to understand that too, because I think it's important to,
again, not only like, it's like a, kind of like a service objection.
There's sales objections where we will plant the seeds ahead of time to deal
with the objections ahead of time.
This is also kind of setting the ground for the service.
So they understand that in month six we're probably just gonna be sending them
content briefs or doing content for them and or building links, right?
So they're not gonna be sitting there and, and six months we can tell them that,
look it, we have this conversation, right? You looked,
you in the face and I told you that in month six the work's gonna be a lot
slower and I also gave you that option to pay us just for that work
at this time.
But you chose to amortize it and split it up over the life of this so that way
you didn't get hit with an upfront bill. You know? So yeah, I mean you could,
you can definitely do it that way. I present it to 'em that way. Again,
that's why that's,
that pricing spreadsheet is probably the simplest template that we have here,
but it's also one of the most effective because it's such a great communication
tool. Um, more than anything.
Just had a, speaking on that, I,
I was super confused about the sprint versus monthly and at first I thought it
had to be completely sprint based and blah, blah, blah. I had,
after talking to Ryan a couple times, I just had a lady this morning, uh,
it was 10 grand for the package that we're doing for,
she asked me if we could break it up into four monthly payments of 2,500 a
piece. Um, I did that. And so it finally,
it's been clicking a little bit at a time, uh, that she was on the sprints plan.
We're doing three different sprints for her,
but she's still basically paying monthly for it at 2,500 a month,
which was what we were charging people before.
But the sprint model allowed me to,
not only it made it easier to sell her,
but it also let me kind of deposition other ss e o companies gave me like
a unique positioning of my service versus theirs. And it,
it all kind of just made sense. And, and before that happened this morning, uh,
Brian, because you were saying that we could ask you, you know,
if we want certain days on certain things,
I was thinking that maybe even an hour just going over sprints versus monthly
and kind of clarifying that out and building that into the program just so you,
you're kind of focused on it and, and kind of make it clear for everybody.
'cause that was the biggest thing that I struggled with in all of this was,
was the differentiator there of, but, but it,
I figured out that it's really just,
we're pitching sprints and we do all the work at once,
but we can split up the billing to whatever works for them. And,
and that really helped me bring this lady home on this particular one this
morning.
Nice. Very nice. Yeah, I'm glad.
I feel like that was your biggest question coming in here Now. I'm,
I'm glad we got that. Hopefully you got your money's worth. Yeah.
Oh, by, by far already. Yeah.
Um, Connor asked, are you a firm of, are you,
are you a firm QuickBooks fan or you've always just used it?
I'm gonna give you my opinion on this because you know, kind,
I know you're just getting started, but like,
finance is something that you should outsource immediately.
As soon as you get a little bit of budget to dealing with your books
is not a good use of your time.
I think understanding it is a good use of your time, right? And actually, it,
it's, I, I went to, I went back and got my M B A, um,
when I was working big consulting, this was back 10,
12 years ago when MBAs, I think had a lot more weight.
And in the corporate world it made a lot more sense to move up.
I didn't learn a whole lot aside from the fact that what they were teaching was
20 years in the past. 'cause they were teaching like supply chain management.
I'm like, yo, everything's made in China. Why are we even talking about this?
But, um, what I did learn a lot about was accounting.
And that was incredibly impactful for me because it helped me to
understand that once a business gets rolling
weird as this is gonna sound once, it's like once a product set.
And so it's just numbers really, right? It's,
it's the management of numbers really that's kind of like what the health of a
business is and understanding
what like cost of goods sold was, what gross margin was, what net profit,
like all these different kind of basic financial things is important for you as
a business owner to know.
It's also important for you to understand how accounting works so you can see
where the money's going and the flow of money.
But if you're sitting down every month and you're going through and building
your books, and if you're not doing monthly accounting, like it's, it's a,
it's a big, big swing and a miss. You definitely should be.
So I don't know anything about QuickBooks.
I've used it once and it's cool.
It's what our accounting firm chooses to use.
It's also widely understood by most tax accountants, right? So like,
also keep in mind that our financial accountant does our day-to-day bookkeeping
invoicing,
but we also have a separate tax accountant that at the end of the year takes the
QuickBooks and then, you know, builds out our, our tax reports. So, um,
if you're doing it, QuickBooks is cool.
I'm sure there's some ch I think wave is also,
wave is probably a better one if you're doing it yourself. I know we used to,
when we first launched the blueprint, David was doing our accounting, David,
my partner, uh, and he would use Wave. Um, 'cause it's kind of like a good
solopreneur. FreshBooks is fine. Yeah, FreshBooks is cool too. Um,
for everyone listening though,
like it is really important that you do keep your books on a monthly basis.
I know it sucks if you're doing it by yourself, but it's really,
really important because
I'm sure all of you know this, but if you're just getting started, you know,
it's important to understand that the money that your business makes does not
belong to you. It belongs to the business, right?
The business has to have its own accounting, its own bank account,
and you get paid off of the bottom line of the business,
not the top line.
What that means is that the business has to be able to pay out contract or
expenses overhead. And when it, that's a kind of,
the beautiful thing about this model when you're first getting started is that
you don't have a lot of expenses.
It's really just like software for the most part. Um,
but all that stuff gets paid before you do. I have seen so many people,
I had a friend actually in the s e o space who was back in like the 2010,
2012 like source wave days if anyone's been in the game for that long. Um,
he made a lot of money, a lot,
a lot of money as like one of the first kind of adopters of like the black gray
hat, I think building P B N S E O stuff, which of course didn't last long.
So he, he made a lot of money, but he didn't,
he didn't do well with his money anyways.
The som come down to Miami below it all on a lot of stuff, not Becker,
but somebody in kind of that ecosystem. Uh,
he rented a penthouse for like 30 Gs a month, you know,
was at strip clubs every week, just, just living large. Of course,
he went broke, um, but he was also living off the top line of the business.
This is something that,
like my wife and I just like butt heads about all the time because we're in
Miami here, man, and people in Miami are just a******s with their money. They,
they like, they think that because they make, I don't know,
call it a hundred grand off their business a year that they make a hundred
grand. Like you don't, you gotta pay everything out. Um,
and whatever's left, if you don't have any partners, you then own the profit.
But before you own that profit,
the United States government owns that profit and you're probably gonna get
taxed at a 28 to 42% depending on how much money you make.
So every dollar a profit that you make times it by 0.7 and that's probably what
you owe own. So not only did he blow through all of his money,
'cause he lived off the top line of the business,
but he also didn't account for taxes and he had a massive, massive,
massive fist up as you know what from the United States government. So,
um, not that anyone here has a problem with that,
just a word of warning that if you're just getting started,
you have to make sure that ear, the earlier the better.
Because I think every entrepreneur goes through this journey. I mean, I did too,
right? I went, I learned that the hard way. Luckily when I first got started,
I wasn't making a lot of money.
So when I had to pay back taxes was only a couple thousand bucks. Um,
paying quarterly is another good one too, Noah, uh,
just to make sure on top of it. Um, but yeah,
like Uncle Sam does not play. This country's in a lot of debt.
They want their money. So, so they're gonna come for that money,
even if it's 10 years later, they're gonna come for it. Um, nester said,
let's all move to Dubai. This 0% income tax. Actually, I've never been to Dubai.
I would love to go. My friend of mine who's actually Saudi, um, SPEs Dubai,
he says it's basically just like built like Disneyland. It's all a front. Um,
but I've heard, I've actually heard it's, it's a great place.
Puerto Rico's another one. Puerto Rico's a lot closer.
You can go to Puerto Rico, um,
and you only have to be there for 51% of the year. But I actually,
Hormoz had like a really good kind of clip on this where he is talking about it
and like,
I just think that moving somewhere just to save money on taxes,
like live where you wanna live, you know,
it's just much easier to focus on growing your business and making more,
or living a different lifestyle. You know,
maybe don't buy that Lamborghini until you hit a certain level,
but it's your money. I'll do what you want with it. Um, or move to Dubai,
move to Puerto Rico, whatever makes you happy. Um, but you know,
the older that you get, you can talk about my, the gray hairs, my beard,
I'm getting older. Um, it's, it gets much,
much more difficult to do that once you got a wife and family and all this
stuff. It becomes very easy to do it. So if you're, if you're young,
enjoy yourself, live across the world, travel, work, remote, do all that.
Uh, I would a hundred percent do it myself. Did it for a while. Actually.
I had a good time. Uh, Noah said,
how does c p a look into places that are better for taxes? I'm oof.
California's rough. He said, I'm in California. And he came back with it.
No matter where you go, they will always get your money one way or the other.
Maybe it's less income tax,
but it's more of other taxes they get paid either way. Yeah,
the government's gonna get their money even if they do nothing for us,
the government is gonna get their damn money. Um, I live in Florida also,
by the way, which is good. I'm from Massachusetts. That has,
and they actually just implemented this too, the millionaires tax,
which if you make over a million bucks, they take I think 40 something stupid.
They take like an absurd amount of money from from you, like a next.
I think that it's, and it,
it's a 10% state tax that they put on top of your federal tax,
which is mind blowingly nuts. Um, and yeah,
Florida has no state income taxes, which is great Texas also. Um,
that's why a lot of people have moved to Florida and Texas, um,
from California anyways, but California's a beautiful, beautiful place,
so it can be tough to leave. Weather's amazing. Um, cool.
Uh, I mean we can keep talking s**t about any what, whatever you want,
but if anybody has any questions about training, also too, now's a good time.
Um, you know, tell me about what else you wanna see from these next sessions.
Uh,
while you guys think of that stuff for the next couple sessions that we have.
If you want to submit proposals, if you want to do some sample analysis,
uh, and drop 'em into Slack or just DMM them to me, um, you know,
I'll take a quick look at it and then we can go over it on the next couple of
calls. Happy to look at anything that you have, um,
in relation to sales. Again, analysis.
If you want to spend some time on the next call,
going through another live analysis, you know, submit a website,
we can just kind of go through the whole process. My, again, my time is yours.
We've got three more of these calls set, so, um, we can come on,
talk about whatever you want. You wanna talk about N B A,
I'm down big Celtics fan, you know, hopefully we win in all this year. But, um,
you know, my time is yours to talk about sales here as well. So, um,
whatever you all want, just think about it. Dmm me on Slack,
drop it in the channel, uh, whatever. Does anybody else have any more questions?
Anything else they wanna talk about today?
Not that I can think of. One question I have on Yeah.
On finances, when you are for services,
since there's really not like any, uh, cost of like,
typically gross is calculated for like the cost of the good, but in this case,
in services, it's like the cost of the service. So for like gross margins,
do you use like cost of service Yeah. In, in that?
Yep. Good question. So most people would tell you no.
Uh, but I learned this the hard way at the agency that bought my agency
was a, was great at marketing,
but financially the C F O, and this is not a knock on him. It, it was,
it was a little bit overwhelming for him when,
because the agency that bought mine also bought another social agency. So like,
like it was a big thing that he wanted to make this like full stack digital
agency just over leveraged in terms of debt in the company,
in terms of purchasing these other agencies in terms of position redundancy,
in terms of all these different clients. It was just like a financial nightmare.
Um,
and what happened was was that traditionally an agency,
right? People are, people are an expense,
they're not. So, okay, for, for, just, let me break this down.
So for those you don't know, financial accounting, you have your revenue, right?
Then you have what's called your cogs, your cost of goods sold.
So if it's Apple, right,
it's gonna be the cost to make the product. So materials,
labor that goes into directly supporting this,
that would be your cost of goods sold. So as an agency,
we don't have a physical product.
So salaries for people actually gets put down to the next stage,
which is expenses. So again, revenue at the very top line, cost of goods sold.
And then you have your gross profit, your gross profit margin.
That's basically like what is your profit after your product, right?
So if you're an e-commerce or if you're making a physical product,
that's a really important margin because you wanna understand how much your
product's costing, right?
Then after that you've got your line of expenses and that's where like your
rent, your software, your salary, so like corporate salaries,
that's where they go. And then you've got your net profit at the bottom,
a k a ebitda, um, ex
expenses, no, I'm sorry, EBITDA is before interest,
before interest in taxes basically. So basically your, your taxable income is,
is your net profit margin. That's what people,
when what people refer to a profit, it's your net profit.
So after all is expenses. And that's basically again,
what you live on before taxes. So the way that I like to look at it.
And a lot of people agree with me,
A lot of people may not agree with me or they just don't look at it this way.
Was that from an agency? When we were doing our accounting at the other agency,
our, our cost of goods sold was, was nothing. Right?
Because we didn't technically have a product. So everything was an expenses,
and when you lump everything into expenses,
you're not really getting accurate picture on your most important expense,
which is labor, right? So what ended up happening was,
was that it was basically just a running list of expenses at the business.
And there was a million things going in, right? Plus like,
it was just a very difficult way to account for that business.
So after going through that process,
because frankly we just didn't have a good handle on our numbers,
and it created so much chaos, so much chaos, um,
from an owner point of view in terms of what we were actually making that
after I left that I decided that we were going to make sure to account in
a service-based business as our people in contractors,
and also software as a cost of sold.
So essentially anything that is directly used on a client account
is a cost of goods sold. So that goes into our gross profit margin.
'cause our gross profit margins really under, it's really,
really important for us to understand what it's costing us to run the business,
to run our services, to build our product, right? So again,
our service is our product at these businesses. So I actually had to go through,
when we first hired her name's Leandra,
our accountant had to go back and rebuild all the books with her to dig out
people costs. So we have our employees and then we have our contractors,
and then we have our software costs in there as well.
Any software that we're using to, so like hres, um,
uh, like our, I don't know, whatever that goes into, right?
Those go directly into cost of good cost of goods sold.
Now we can clearly see what our service margin is. 'cause that's important,
right? When it comes to hiring staff,
when it comes to understanding what we should be pricing,
we need to understand what is costing us, what our margin is on our service.
And then after that, we'll put our expenses in terms of, um,
you know, like we have an office space, you know, Caesar has an office.
We've got all these different offices for like,
so our people across the country, across the world. Um, we'll put that in there.
And then also we'll look at software depending on if we're using it for a client
versus if we're using it for the business.
So like accounting software for example, goes into the expenses.
That's not a client expense or client cost,
that's a business expense and a business cost.
So now we're clearly able to see and on a monthly basis, yearly basis,
understand what our service and product is costing us versus what the business
is costing us.
And that allows us to make a lot more educated decisions about what we
may or may not want to cut in terms of, um, software in terms of people costs,
all the above. So
Like sales software would, would be a, a, a classic expense,
not a cost of goods service.
Yeah. We, we, we account for,
for sales commissions as a business expense because it doesn't
directly support the client, right?
So if we were to put sales commissions in our, in our cost of goods sold,
then it would really conflate the numbers, right? Because same thing
With advertising, uh,
fee costs and referral fees to like partners or something like that.
Exactly. Those are business expenses.
How do you put, so for contractors that,
that makes a lot of sense to keep in cost of goods sold,
but for employees that, that seems a little bit harder, especially for like,
since you have a number of like operational people. Um,
I guess maybe I'm thinking more of the blueprint,
but is there certain employees that you don't put in cost of goods sold?
Yep. I, so I'm not a cost of goods sold and Caesar's not a cost of goods sold.
'cause Caesar, while he supports clients, he's also,
he's a, he's a basically a partner at the company. And same with Jan.
Like Jan is Jan's on payroll for Webers too. 'cause he runs our ads, uh,
and also helps me out with marketing.
But he's a business expense content writers that we use to,
to write podcast video editors. Those are all business expenses,
not client expenses. So basically, you know,
the people that we have working on clients only work on client stuff.
And I think that's the only way to do it.
That was another big mistake that this agency before us made was that the
founder, who I'm still great, good friends with, I I,
I really respect him a lot as an entrepreneur and as a,
as an agency owner and all this whatnot.
But he had this idea kind of like Gary V,
that like he wanted to build an agency that had a lot of talent that he could
then deploy against his own portfolio of businesses, right?
And build his own portfolio businesses. You can't do that. It did, like,
it was very clear to me when I first got there that it didn't work because
again, we are here to, to make our clients more money.
That's what we talked about all throughout sales.
That's what like the mantra of an agency should be.
We are here to make our clients money.
So that means their only focus if they're working on client account should be
that they shouldn't be working on blog content for the business.
You basically can't squeeze this out of them. And especially too,
it's not fair to the employee to hire them to do a job and then ask them to just
take on more work for, for no additional pace. It's not cool, right?
So it leads to burnout, it leads to dissension, it leads to turnover,
all the different stuff. So we clearly categorize our,
our people based on the role that they have, the business.
So if you work on like our ss e o team for clients, you're cost of good sold.
That doesn't mean you're any different.
We don't look at you any different in terms of the business,
in terms of all that different stuff.
But it also helps us to understand pay bands. It helps us to understand,
you know, raises and bonuses that we give at the year end.
Like all that different stuff. Um,
so if you're not working on client stuff and you're working on anything for the
business, like marketing, advertising, accounting, um,
any of those things, then you're the second line of expenses.
Two more questions on this thing. Yeah. Um, on this topic, uh, for your,
like your net margins, like what's it,
I've heard you talk about like 80%,
I've heard other people talk about 50% and other, you know,
hormones you're talking about like, I wouldn't do a,
a service-based business if it was, if it wasn't 80%. Like that's our,
our standard, um, is that,
and that is like after a contractor expenses?
Yeah. Okay. 80%. 80%. So like when I talk about, I, I'm, uh,
so we're at, I'll tell you this, we're at about 75% gross margin.
And that's the number that I'm usually referring to our net profit at the end of
LA because this is the thing too,
is that like the thing about profit is that like,
it's so easy manipulated up and down. Like if you're a PE firm, for example,
right? And you're gonna buy, or you're gonna buy a business,
you're looking at expenses in terms of what can I cut to get that number up?
And if you're gonna sell the business, you're also looking like,
I could cut yawn,
I could cut our counter and I could cut our advertising expense of the business
and get our net profit up to 55, 60% overnight. Um,
but I would never do that because I'm trying to build and grow the business,
right? So like, we spend a lot of money on advertising and whatnot.
So that net profit number, like, it,
it, it usually hovers around 40% at the year end, right? For us,
our net net net profit, and that's like my profit, basically. Okay.
I guess that, I guess I meant to say gross because that's like, yeah,
that exactly. So like 75% is what we aim to stick at. Um,
and that's also like, we look at that, that that's like,
that's the K P i that Cesar and I look at, at a,
basically a quarterly basis we're looking at our gross profit margin.
Because if that number is going down,
then it usually means that we're probably not, we we're not selling enough,
right? Um, because our, there,
our labor kind of costs re remains the same, or if it's really high,
then it probably means we, it's time to hire more, right?
If that number shoots up to 90%, then I would also, like,
we're also in touch with our team obviously,
but like that would indicate to me that like,
it's time we need to hire somebody else because these people,
if they're not already burned out, they're gonna get burned out. Um,
or we're just signing much bigger clients. So there's then,
so like that's the number that we're looking at in analyzing.
'cause the net profit at the end, like I said, I look at the net profit, like,
because I own 90% of the business where, so whatever's left over at the end,
that's usually what I take home. I take a,
I take a monthly salary from the business, but it's, it's, it's nominal.
It's minimal. I get paid almost everything at the end of the year.
But that also means for me then that I'm looking at being like, if I,
if that net profit number is really high, then I'm hiring,
then I'm going out and at the end of the year I'm spending on content,
I'm spending on ads, right? I'm,
I'm basically earmarking that to be spent on the business to help it grow. Um,
but that doesn't mean that I'm gonna go out and hire like another s e o
strategist because of that gr like that.
So that's like different levels of profit that I'm looking at to understand
which lever to pull in the business. So when somebody like OSI says 80%,
like I really like and respect the guy, but I would've to call b******t on that.
'cause if you're an, like,
if you're a service business that's operating and doing more than a million
dollars a year at 80% net profit,
you're probably like a solopreneur or like working with vass. And you know,
I would just really ha and like, I know I I,
I have a friend who hired his company and their s**t.
He owns a gym and like their business is s**t. It's a terrible, it's a terrible,
terrible, terrible business. And they have a bunch of people too.
So it's not like it's an automated system. Like it's not, there's just no,
there's just no, I would find it very, very hard for them to be doing.
'cause they don't charge that much either.
They charge like 15 grand for the year. So just off that,
they have like Facebook ads people, they have all this different stuff.
They're like very well systematized, but like 80% profit,
like net profit at the bottom of that would be, I mean, I would,
I would be very impressed if that was the case,
but I would kind of mid and I would kind of call b******t on that.
That's why again, too, like when people talk about profit,
I usually will kind of push back and be like, well what's your gross?
And they'll be like, well we don't really track gross. Like yeah, exactly.
So it's, it's a, it's a,
it's a finicky number, right? Because I said a lot of businesses,
especially once you've been done this for a while and like you've been through
like the, the m and a where like you bought, you sold,
you understand how easily that number can be, can be jacked up very quickly.
And unfortunately it's usually by cutting people, um, mass cutting expenses,
especially in the short term, right? Like I could cut our ad spend alone,
I cut our marketing spend alone. 'cause we spend upwards of,
between advertising, between people content,
like 30,000 to 40,000 a month at Webers alone. You know,
so like if I cut that for three months and then use that last
quarter to as like, what I'm looking as somebody to buy, they'd be like,
holy s**t,
like this business looks great and the pipeline would still be fine because the
advertising would've, would've filled our pipeline enough.
So if and when I do sell the business, I mean that's exactly what I would do.
And I would look at the trailing quarter as like the key, you know,
marquee of that.
Or I would flip heavily to try and work off referrals for six to 12 months to
to, to at least maintain revenue for a year and then, and then try and sell it.
Because basically for those who do care,
and I know we're getting off topic here, but when you sell a business,
they're looking at the net profit number and the multiple comes off that net
profit number. A lot of people get confused about that.
Like they'll do a million in revenue and be like, oh,
well agencies usually trade for three x multiple, so $3 million.
Like no, no, no, no, it's off the net profit for the,
for the trailing 12 months. Um, which means if you do,
if your net is 20%, that means 200 grand.
That means you're gonna sell the business for 600 grand max if that,
if you get a three x multiple, most agencies don't even get that. Um,
so yeah, I mean these are good conversations to have.
I think from a business point of view,
these are things that we don't get to talk about a lot.
So I'm glad you guys are asking. Um, lemme go over the comments here real quick.
Michael asked, do you use any hard close sales taxes at the end? Are,
are you able to build up so much value in the process and touch points that
people will just sign? Um, it's a good question.
So it's a case by case basis. I think that with law firms,
it's really difficult for me to do that because of all the things that Andrew
and I discussed in terms of they're being really busy, um,
being difficult to also like drill into who the actual decision maker is.
Because sometimes I'll talk to, like, sometimes I'm talking to like a secretary,
uh, with law firms, right? Because they'll just kind of dump some of that,
like the, the, the managing partner will like find us,
dump it on the secretary to like interview. So like,
and then they kind of play gatekeeper. It can be a little bit annoying, but
I liken it to like more of a blueprint style where we definitely use a lot more
hard closes and like sc and like true tactics, like scarcity, um,
like price bumps, bundles, things like that.
Because our product here is mostly informational.
So we're able to do that, um, without necessarily eroding our margin.
So some things that you can do at, it's, it's,
it's more difficult to do at the agency side because for example,
like we're doing, we're, so this bootcamp for example, right?
We're selling this bootcamp, we're starting to advertise it, um,
as you can buy the trainings, right? For i, I don't know,
a couple thousand bucks, right?
But we're gonna bump that price up after two weeks. That's like a,
to me that's like a hard closed scarcity tactic, right?
So our sales reps are I to sneeze? I'm sorry. Our sales reps are,
of course when I say it, I don't have to go anymore. Okay?
So our sales reps are using that scarcity tactic to go back through people that
they talked to before and try and hard close them with that deal, that discount,
using that deadline scarcity, uh, you know, price increase.
It can be difficult to do that with the agency stuff because if you,
if you're like, Hey, I sent you this proposal,
if you close by at the end of the week, if not,
if you don't close by the end the week I'm raising it to 10,000 bucks,
you're gonna be like, well, you just scoped. Like, what, how does that work? It,
it, it doesn't really kind of translate one to one. Again, some of the,
the scarcity tactics that you can use are letting 'em know that the proposal
expires, right? Um, and then drilling home with them that,
and they might not care. That's the thing too, is that, like I say,
this is on a case by case basis because,
and the reason why this whole process is so important,
'cause you wanna try and get this information,
like are you talking to other agencies?
How many proposals are you getting at this time?
'cause if they're getting five proposals, three proposals and you're like, Hey,
if you don't close by the end of this week this proposal expires,
it'll probably be like, okay, like say vy, you know, like, I really liked you,
but there's not much I can do. Um, so it's a case by case basis,
understanding where they are, how many people they're talking to, uh,
all these different things. But in terms of hard closes, like, yes, I will,
like the deadline is kind of the best thing, right?
Just to let them know that you told me you'd have this by this date.
I just wanna let you know that in two weeks I have this proposal just has to
expire because, you know, we're constantly changing.
I tell this to people all the time, um, as kind of like a,
not quite a hard sell tactic, but when I look at my calendar,
my calendar's always full.
So I'm usually sharing my screen on these calls with them.
When I'm going through the documentation, the analysis, I'll be like, Hey,
look at, you know, uh, especially when I'm booking like the follow-up call,
I'll be like, just so you know,
like there's so much demand for our services right now for this offer.
We've really, and this is another thing too, Andrew too, that we're tying into,
like things you could tell them is kind of like pushing this new hook angle on
them that like, like this thing that just came out with Google,
with like the AI stuff.
Like these are all opportunities for you to kind of like sync your hook back
into people. So for example, if I'm trying to give a hard close with somebody,
I have my calendar open, they see it filled with appointments. I'm like,
this new offer that we're running,
like we've really got this AI thing figured out. I don't know if you saw it,
Google just released x, y,
Z information and our agency's one of the only ones in the world that really
knows what we're doing around this.
'cause we've been prepping around this for six months and I've got a video on my
YouTube channel you can check out if you want just for proof to, to,
to show you that I was,
I've been talking about this forever and now it's finally here.
And we can't keep up with the demand.
Like by just kind of seeding those things in the back of their mind that like,
people are after you and they wanna work with you.
It allows you to use more of a hard close and a scarcity angle.
But if you're not able to set those hooks,
if they're talking to a lot of people, if they're hyper price sensitive,
if it's just out of their hands. Because if they're like,
I really wanna work with you Ryan, but like, what do you want me to do? Like,
I'm, I, I like, it's not my money, it's my boss's money.
Like I I I need him to approve this. Um, then there's not a lot you can do.
The other thing with that though is just to make sure that you could, you could
aim to get the decision maker on the calls. It's, I,
I don't think I mentioned this before,
but like after going through the discovery call,
you always wanna make sure that you know who all the players are in the process.
So one of the questions to, to usually ask in the discovery process,
I don't know if it's in temp or not, but, um,
who's making the final decision on this, right? Um,
what does that process look like? Uh, do you have a budget you to hit?
Do you have a, you know, a manager, an executive that needs to approve this?
If so, we need to get 'em on the next call, right?
I need to make sure that everyone sees this information.
It's just gonna save us all a lot of time. Um, Noah asked,
can we talk about how you guys using AI so far in the agency? Yeah, absolutely.
Um, we're actually using chat BT to write a lot of content now. Uh,
I just found that out. Um, my content team told me we,
we just hired like three writers. Two of them are crap,
so we only one of them stuck. Um, and our content,
our s e o content guy has been using, uh,
chat g p t very effectively and the content is actually doing pretty well. Um,
it's ranking. So, uh,
we're basically just using it to help write content right now.
That's pretty much it. Um,
aside from the fact that like every single software now was like powered by ai.
So like, technically you could say that like everything we're doing,
it's like the new marketing buzzword. Um, it's kinda like Google, you know,
I saw the,
had a good discussion with our team internally yesterday on a Monday call about
the Google i io stuff that they just released.
And we were talking about it together as a team and really looking at it,
Cyrus Shepherd also had a pretty good Twitter thread to look him up.
Cyrus Shepherd, I think I talked about it before on here.
He had like a like kind of good,
a good analysis of what his thoughts were on the release of it.
But the way that I looked at it was that it's basically just
like Google's, this is just my opinion,
but Google's been using AI in their algorithms for, for years.
Like it's not new, right? They're not like,
I don't think they're really like reshifting how they rank things because AI has
been a factor for them forever, right?
The way that I look at it from what they re-released is like,
it looks like it's just a better UI for Google search.
It's kinda what it looked like to me is basically just like,
if you think about it this way,
if you strip away what Google looks like from the front end and the back end of
what's running, it's the same thing that didn't change anything.
All they're doing is they're sending that information in a way that they think
users and searchers are gonna prefer more. And to me,
like just like I talked about,
like that top funnel stuff that's like informational,
like the example that they gave, like if you see how long that search was,
it was like, what's better for kids with less than for three kids,
less than five for like Bryce Canyon or like Arch Rock,
like this massively long,
long tail search that has absolutely no business value.
And they like use the AI to summarize it.
And then there's still cards in the search for you to click to find more.
So it's potentially cannibalizing traffic, but like a,
it's not that good of traffic and b,
they're still citing places for you to go and and view more,
which you're probably gonna wanna do as a searcher.
The other big thing was with shopping,
like essentially it's just a new serp,
like all the products that are in there that you can like shop and compare
against. Like it's just like Google search now that they're already doing,
that they've already been doing right. Um, so it's just, like I said,
it's like a new, a new and better UI on top of it,
but we'll see how searchers use it. And then the third one was,
they talked about how ads are still,
they think ads are still an important part of the searcher journey and there's
still gonna be a part of it. So if there's still ads in there,
nothing is really gonna change that much.
I'm actually feeling like a lot better after seeing this about
the future of, of search and how I still think it's,
it's not gonna really have that much of a hiccup in terms of like,
people losing traffic. I mean, people will lose traffic, I think. Um, but again,
I think if you take this bottom up approach as pro,
as opposed to this top down approach and like you don't go after keywords that
have no business value and just focus on keywords that have business value and
still have ads, we'll be fine. Um, uh,
Nestor asks,
is there a minimum amount of sales reps to hire for an agency?
What do you mean by that? Nestor?
Sorry man, I've, I'm, uh, I'm, I'm, I'm only like two hours of sleep,
so I'm like not making these. No, you're
Good.
Um,
so is there a minimum amount of sales reps that you like?
Is there an amount? No, that's not the, that's not the best way to to,
to ask a question. So how many sales reps would you recommend that a,
that an agency hires,
like let's say at the beginning stage where you're,
let's say you have maybe five clients,
you've reached a 10 k a month mark,
what would you recommend? One or two or
So? Okay, good question. Now I get it. So I think,
so the reason why I didn't talk a lot on this,
and maybe that's another good topic that we can do for another one,
is like bring on a sales rep and like comp plans and all that different stuff.
Um, we didn't talk about it 'cause I, I just, from the beginning of this,
it seemed like everyone except for maybe Austin, I think is pretty much doing,
you know, their own,
their own sales and will probably continue that way in terms of hiring a rep.
I think it's the last position that you should hire for in an agency. So,
and that's, unless you're like really, really, really bad at sales and you,
you just can't get it figured out. But like, you kind of have to, 'cause it's,
it's like I said,
if you're a consultant and you're able to do SEO o then you should be able to
sell it, right? That's my opinion.
And that's kind of the point of this whole bootcamp.
But it should be the last hire that you make.
That means like you should hire everyone first that's gonna do the actual
service delivery for you. Right?
After that you should probably hire some sort of like project or account manager
to help stay everything organized, right?
And then after that then is when you can bring in a sales rep.
I don't know what that revenue number looks like per se.
It's gonna be a lot more than $10,000 a month. But until that point you,
the managing partner, the founder,
a partner should always be handling the sales because
you're just gonna be the most effective at it.
And I think the other positions are more important, right?
You really wanna make sure that you have people.
'cause the most time consuming thing is actually delivering the service. Yeah.
Um,
so you wanna replace yourself there first after that start with one because it's
really the,
the number of sales reps you hire is gonna be dependent on how many leads you
have.
So we've talked about this a little bit in terms of like a lower ticket service,
500,000, $1,500 a month, you're gonna need a lot of leads to grow that.
In that case you might want to hire a couple of sales reps. Um,
it also depends on how you're generating leads.
If you're using like a cold outbound method, dialing outbound emails,
whatever, then and you're only paying on commission,
bring on as many reps as possible, right?
Bring on three at a time and whoever sticks, it's like a sink or swim situation,
right? They gotta generate their own leads, they gotta close them.
Then you just give them the proper arsenal and training. And again,
I know a company here in Miami that does five, 10,
15 million a year selling just local s e o to people who just,
their whole model is, they just go and find like hungry, hungry kids who,
and they give them the training on how to basically generate and close their own
leads and they're just like hired guns. They just pay 'em on commission.
So it's really no, there's really no
risk for the business, if you will, in terms of bringing on a lot of reps.
The way that I comp my reps though is different because we have a different
model where they've gotta have a certain level of expertise, right?
We're talking to usually people that know what they're talking about.
We're talking about contracts 50 K and up. So we pay a base plus a commission.
So our base is like 3000 a month and then we pay a rate on top of that as well.
Um, because I know in order to get that type of person,
they're gonna have to make at least a hundred grand a year, um, in order to,
to to, to fulfill that sales. So it just depends on what the stage is,
what you're selling and how you're generating leads. But for the most part,
you know, one rep is, is more than enough. 'cause if,
if you have a couple of reps in the reliant on you for leads,
you know, leads are kind of a roller coaster. Sometimes, like some,
some months we'll do 60, some months we'll do 10. Right.
And if you have two people eating off that, then it can create some challenges.
Some, some, some, some headaches for sure. Uh,
Connor said,
you mentioned about taking a small salary then taking distributions at the end
of the year. Does that mean their taxes and S-corp? Yeah, good question.
So there's three LLCs that I own and operate. I have Webers,
L L C I have the blueprint training, L L C and I have Ryan Stewart Consulting,
L L c. All of those get paid in by clients, right? And then I have,
Ryan was here incorporated, that's an S-corp.
So those three LLCs pay into my S-corp, right?
And then my S-corp pays me a monthly payroll salary
from the SS corp. So I reduce my payroll tax.
So I mean my taxes at the end of the year, I just, I just got 'em done. It was,
it's a mission because I have to do three business taxes, right?
And then I have to do taxes on my SS corp, which is technically a business.
Then I also have my personal taxes at the end of the year. But technically,
if you're set up as an S-corp, everything that my,
all my ownership shares as an L L C, they pass through to my S-corp.
So that's why at the end of the year too,
another great thing about these businesses with no overhead is that I can just
flush the cash through, right? If you can't flush the cash through,
then you're still liable for the taxes on these companies.
If you have to hold half a million bucks in a company,
I'm still getting taxed on that,
which sucks because it technically doesn't hit my getting taxed on something
that sits in my business.
So the way that my account set me up was based on these business models,
was to flush them all through. 'cause I, at the end of the year,
we just flush it.
We pay bonuses to all our employees and then we flush out the cash directly to
me. Uh, and my partner I in the business as well. Um,
Andrew said three cards of the new, this is going back to the AI search results,
three cards of the new top positions.
They didn't show how the service took on mobile.
Do the three cards show up on mobile? Don't know. Yeah,
I didn't see that either. I think I did see a screenshot.
They ha I mean we'll find out soon enough.
I think this is gonna be rolling out in a co in a couple of weeks. Um,
I also just think too, like the big thing here is like,
are people gonna actually like using this? You know,
we're under the assumption that like people love it, but uh, like I,
I use chat G P T, but I use it for specific things.
I don't use it for everything, right?
I don't use it as a search and it's not connected to the internet,
which is a whole thing. But like, you know, I don't use it for everything.
So I think the user behavior will actually determine how much we use this. Um,
'cause like I said, at the end of the day you really zoom out.
This is basically just a new ui.
'cause like I looked at it too as like what they showed.
It's kind of like people already ask, it's kind of like the fill in the search.
It's kind of like the cards, like the, the little dropdowns underneath.
So to me it's just kind of like a more truncated way of visualizing the search
and all the results are still under underneath.
And I still think that a lot of these searches,
people want the variety to look around and,
and click around in different things, especially on desktop. 'cause I,
I mean I'm a, I'm a 30 tab at a time person myself. Anyways,
Noah said AI tip one great chat.
G p t prompt we've been killing it with is to say, uh, before you start writing,
do you have any questions for me?
It will then ask you clarifying questions to prompt in most cases.
Sometimes it doesn't. Not sure why. It's a good one. It's a good one. Um,
Andrew said, I try to set up the con the content for the prompt.
I'm an SEO O expert targeting law firms, et cetera. Good tips. Good tips. Yeah,
same thing. No too, like I said,
it was diff it's difficult for me to like build a process around it because
every time it spits out something a little bit different,
which is a little bit frustrating, but I guess it's ai, you know, so it
Would get better. It'll
Get better. Yeah. But I also think that's kind of part of it, right?
Is that like,
and maybe it makes you feel better about using AI to write content because it
tells you that somebody else gives it the same prompt to write the exact same
article. That'll be a little bit different. You know,
I just read something yesterday too that there, uh, chat,
G P T or Open AI is dropping a browser inside chat G P T that
will connect to the internet, that will be able to go scan stuff and,
and bring more current data. So I'm curious to see what that looks like. Yeah,
Yep. Yeah, and it's interesting. Google just steps on Go ahead.
I was gonna say,
you can also use a plugin for the browser plugin for chat G P T to get, uh,
live data and, and or put in links,
actual links to websites and pages to have it person read, which is cool.
There'll be,
there'll be AI s e o sooner or later where we're just trying to get people to
come up as answers for the AI too.
Yeah, I think, I think that's a good point though, is that,
and that was kinda what I was getting to too, is that like,
it kind of already is ai s e o, right?
Because we're already optimizing against ai. It's really just a matter of
if, I think the big thing is just that people are are out and actually saw,
like, you know,
Rand Fishkin tweeted out this whole thing about how he was so upset about how
like all these publishers work so hard and like Google's just stealing their
traffic. I'm like, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on. First of all,
Google doesn't know us anything.
Every single person on this call has made a living fed their family off of a
platform that they built for free. That these founders took all the risk spent,
all the money went through all this stress, they built it,
they can do whatever the hell they want with it. It's like,
this like really bothers me when people have this, it's like a mindset thing.
It's like a victim mindset. Like we've all made so much money off this platform.
Like we should be like thanking Google, right?
And Google has a responsibility to their customers to do what's best for them.
And I don't think anyone would argue that like moving to an AI driven search
model, they have to do, it's what's best for customers.
So sit there and be like, oh, like Google's cannibalizing this traffic. Like,
no, no, no, you never build a house on rented property, right?
Like same thing with Facebook. People get mad at Facebook thinking about it.
Instagram, it's like they're running a business.
If you have a problem with it builds your own social network and see how,
see how hard it's, you know, like if anything take the mindset of being like,
okay, this is happening. There's nothing I can do about it.
It's my job to figure out the next step of how to make money.
That's the right mindset. It's
Kind of whiny anyway.
It's so wi it's and R's a nice guy. I had no issue with him,
but like I saw that and I had to go in on it because I'm like,
this is just like stop spreading this information. Like stop,
stop making people feel like they like, like shaking their fist at Google.
Like no, it's not that. Like they're, they're running a business dude.
Like we want to do, what do you want 'em to do? Um,
word. Um, all right, well I'm gonna wrap this today.
So I got a note here from Austin too.
You said love to see one or two pre, uh, predis site breakdowns if possible.
Just want to help, uh, understanding the, creating a systematized progression.
Absolutely. We can talk about that in the next call. Um,
we'll go through some more analysis. Austin,
if you also have some websites in mind that you might need some help with or in
your pipeline,
like drop 'em to me and we'll take a look and go through 'em on the next call.
Thank you. Um, but yeah,
I appreciate you all and have a great day. We'll talk
One super, super quick question if I can on, on my calendar invites.
It's saying something about homework for this week.
Yeah, so, so homework. I, I don't like that term.
I don't want you guys to feel like,
so basically what I said was that thanks for asking no is that if you want to
put together a proposal,
if you have a proposal or an analysis you wanna put together analysis,
I'm happy to take a look at it on the call.
Just drop me on Slack and we'll go through it on the next call.
You don't have to, obviously I don't wanna give you guys more work to do,
but that's what I was telling Austin 'cause I know Austin sent me a message and
he said he really wants to go through the pre-discovery process in terms of
analyzing, getting context for that stuff. So it's kind of an open format here.
Um,
at this point I'm not gonna make everyone do a proposal 'cause I know you're all
busy. But if you have a proposal, uh, if you wanna work on one in the template,
what we talked about here, then yeah, I'll go through it. Also too,
if anyone wants to do like a, you know,
like dummy discovery call or analysis call, you know,
I'm happy to call you up and we can go through that together. So, um,
but obviously you got a voice up. I'm not gonna like, uh, you know,
I'm not gonna make everyone do it. So if
You need something to go through, feel free to use that one that I sent you.
You could hack that one up if you want.
Drops me on Slack just so I remember it. Okay. Alright, cool. Thanks everyone.
We'll talk soon. Thanks guys. Thanks guys. Bye.